Guide to the Records of the Gallatin Arts Festival MC.128
New York University Archives
Records of the Gallatin Arts Festival
1987-1993
1991-1992
New York University Archives
New York University. Gallatin Division
Spanier, Barry
MC.128
3.67 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 3 half manuscript boxes, 1 oversized flat box, 1 folder in a shared oversized flat box, 2 audio cassettes in a shared cassette box, and 4 VHS tapes in a shared manuscript box.
2 audiocassette
4 videocassettes (vhs)
The Gallatin Arts Festival (GAF) is a week-long community-wide celebration of art and the interdisciplinary scholarship of students within New York University's Gallatin School. The festival features student work in the visual and performing arts. The Records of the Gallatin Arts Festival (1987-1993) include promotional materials, newspaper clippings, photographs, budgets, meeting minutes, event programs, NYU publications, performer biographies, questionnaires, and calendars.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Likely donated by Barry Spanier in 1994. The accession number associated with this gift is 94.012.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 6 contains restricted material such as budgets, meeting minutes, agendas, job and fellowship search applications, and meeting rosters. In addition, any materials in the collection that fall under FERPA are also restricted. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the New York University Archives, (212) 998-2646, university-archives@nyu.edu.
Historical Note
The Gallatin Arts Festival (GAF) is a week-long community-wide celebration of art and the interdisciplinary scholarship of students within New York University's Gallatin School. The festival features student work in the visual and performing arts.The Gallatin Arts Festival, which originated in 1992, was a collaborative effort between Professor Laurin Raiken and graduate student Barry Spanier. Under Professor Raiken's guidance, Spanier developed the festival as part of his master's thesis. Since then, GAF has expanded into the largest public event sponsored by the Gallatin School. GAF provides hands-on opportunities for students to gain knowledge of the process required to produce a multidisciplinary arts festival. Under guidance from members of the arts faculty and student affairs, the Student Leadership Team serves as the primary support for the festival. GAF is a learning experience emphasizing the development of ideas and collaborative innovation.
Source: Gallatin Arts Festival; https://wp.nyu.edu/gallatingalleries/gallatin-arts-festival/
Scope and Contents
The Records of the Gallatin Arts Festival (1987-1993) include promotional materials, newspaper clippings, photographs, budgets, meeting minutes, event programs, NYU publications, performer biographies, questionnaires, and calendars. All of this material relates specifically to the 1992 Gallatin Arts Festival.
Festivals.; VHS; Audiocassettes.; Newspaper columns.; Advertisements; Promotional materials; Budgets.; Questionnaires.; Minutes (administrative records); Programs (documents); Photographs.; Memorandums.; Notes (documents); Calendars.; Manhattan (New York, N.Y.); Spanier, Barry; New York University
- General Administration -- Meeting Agendas, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General Administration -- Assorted Memos, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- General Administration -- Performance Programming Schedules, circa 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- General Administration -- Office Facilities, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- General Administration -- Telephone, circa 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- General Administration, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Venues -- Loeb Student Center, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Venues, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Opening Day, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Gallatin Arts Festival Children's Art Fair, 1992 (Box Shared University Archives 063, Vhs 128.0004-128.0005, Box 1, Folder 11)
- Gallatin Arts Festival Children's Art Fair -- Kids Fair Fliers, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Gallatin Arts Festival Town Meeting, 1992 (Box Shared University Archives 151, Audiocassette 128.0001-128.0002, Box Shared University Archives 063, Vhs 128.0003)
- Gallatin Arts Festival Town Meeting -- Fliers, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Gallatin Arts Festival Town Meeting, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Gallatin Arts Festival Bobin Lane, 1992 (Box Shared University Archives 063, Vhs 128.0006)
- Budget -- Student Affairs Budget Advisory Committee (SABAC), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Budget -- General Budget, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Budget -- Gallatin Student Government, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- NYU Resources, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 17-19, Box 2, Folder 1)
- Festival Guest Book, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Post-Festival Questionnaire for Participants, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- General, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Staffing -- Technical, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Artists -- Bios and Backgrounds, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- Artists -- Bios and Backgrounds -- Pearl Primus, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Artists -- Bios and Backgrounds -- Onwin Borde, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Artists -- Bios and Backgrounds -- Art Form Bios, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Marketing -- Ad Sales Package, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Marketing, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Sponsors -- NYU Co-Sponsorships, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Sponsors -- Corporate Sponsorships, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Program Advertising, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
- Program -- Programs, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Program -- Michele Pierson Design, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Program -- Program Inserts, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Publicity Materials -- Calendar, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Publicity Materials -- Postcard, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Publicity Materials -- Passport, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Press Releases, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
- Washington Square News -- WSN Ad Materials, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 16, Box 7, Folder 2)
- Washington Square News -- Ads and Articles, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 5-10)
- NYU Publications - Arts & Sciences Calendar, 1991-1992 (Box Shared University Archives 150, Folder 3)
- NYU Publications -- Hotline, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- NYU Publications -- NYU Today, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Gallatin Publications -- 715 News and Gallatin Today, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Publications -- Wings, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Photographs, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20, Box 5)
- Publications -- Streams, 1987-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- New York City Publications, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3, Box 7, Folder 3-4)
- Administrative Files -- RESTRICTED, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)